Preliminary Inventory to the Poland. Ambasada (Catholic Church) Records, 1924-1945.
Hoover Institution Archives
Poland. Ambasada (Catholic Church) Records,
1924-1945.
80038
Poland. Ambasada (Catholic Church)
44 microfilm reels (0.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, dispatches, studies, log books, statistics, clippings, and printed matter, relating to Polish-Vatican relations, the Catholic Church in Poland, Polish diplomatic relations during World War II, and Polish refugees.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Sikorski Institute, London.
Access Points
Catholic Church--Relations (diplomatic) with Poland.; Catholic Church--Poland.; Refugees.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; Poland.; Poland--Foreign relations--Catholic Church.; Poland--History--Occupation, 1939-1945.
Container List
- Records of the Polish Embassy at the Vatican
  Each year has a numbered positive and negative reel. In most cases the positive reel is the even numbered reel.
  - 1931-33 (Reel 1-2)
  - 1932-33 (Reel 3-4)
  - 1945 (Reel 5-6)
  - 1940 (Reel 7-8)
  - 1941 (Reel 9-10)
  - 1941 (Reel 11-12)
  - 1942-42 (Reel 13-14)
  - 1942-45 (Reel 15-17)
  - 1942-43 (Reel 17-18)
  - 1924-25 (Reel 19-20)
  - 1928-29
  - 1930 (Reel 21-22)
  - 1930-31 (Reel 23-24)
  - 1943-44
  - 1943-44 (Reel 25-26)
  - 1944-45 (Reel 27-28)
  - 1930-32 (Reel 29-30)
  - 1934-35 (Reel 31-32)
  - 1928-30
  - 1935-37 (Reel 33-34)
  - 1937-38 (Reel 35-36)
  - 1938-39 (Reel 37-38)
  - 1942-43 (Reel 39)
  - 1943 (Reel 40)
  - 1942, 1945 (Reel 41)
  - 1945 (Reel 42-43)